

MARTIN MACHEINER, BSC. MOBILE DEVELOPER

Hi, my name is Martin Macheiner and I'm 25 years old. I am from Austria and at the moment I'm studying Mobile Computing in Hagenberg. Apps and mobile devices of any kind are my passion. I prefer writing apps for Android, as it's my favourite platform. But I'm also familiar with iOS and Web development. My first app targeted Android 1.6, so I'm following the Android development process for quite some time. I'm glad that I'm able to connect two of my hobbies: apps and sports. I love to create apps, which help people improving their fitness and their health. I think that's one of the most interesting and exciting topics in the mobile environment.

EDUCATION



2016 - July 2018

University of applied sciences Upper Austria Hagenberg

2013 - 2016

Secondary Technical College Salzburg

2007 - 2012

Master of science - Mobile Computing

Machine Learning, Interactive technologies, Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Software Architecture, agile project management, mobile sports, automotive computing, sensors and wireless technologies

Bachelor of science - Mobile Computing

Project management, Web services, Android, Windows Phone, iOS with Swift and Objective-C, mobile sports. cross platform development with Qt, embedded systems, mobile security and encryption, shell scripts

A-levels

Basics in electronics and electrical engineering, agile project management, introduction into Java, C, Qt/C++, microcontroller and embedded systems, introduction into Linux/Android

PERSONAL INFO

Birthday 11. January 1993

Nationality

Languages German, English (C1) Hobbies Football, Volleyball,



MY KNOWLEDGE

Android (Wear/Things), iOS, Firebase, App publishing,, JavaFx, Web (Dart), Embedded (C/C++), Project management, Computer Vision, Machine Learning





EXPERIENCE



Freeletics

Feb 2016 - June 2016

Salzburger Banken Software (SBS)

July 2015 - Aug 2015

Apps

Android developer intern - 4 months

Working in a feature team, implement cross-device user settings, set up a cloud test environment, take care of offline workout synchronization, implement a discount campaign for a Google featuring (on the Play Store)

Android developer intern - 6 weeks

Writing an app for live monitoring events of ATMs. Google Cloud Messaging was used to communicate with the smartphone. SBS software runs on 55% of all austrian and on 20% of all german ATMs. (www.sbs.co.at)

Published



Developed





△ MY SKILLS

JAVA/KOTLIN

RXJAVA C/C++/C#

DART/ANGULAR

GIT/SVN



🙎 CONTACT

Lederwaschstraße 19, Austria-5580 Tamsweg +43 664 4046225